Guide to the Everett and Evelyn Ortner papers and photographs ARC.306
Brooklyn Historical Society
- Series 10: Brownstone correspondence, 1965-2005; 43521; 0.4 Linear Feet in five folders
  Of note are letters urging local banks to extend mortgage loans to homebuyers in the previously "red-lined" neighborhood of Park Slope in the 1960s.
  - Brownstone correspondence, 1965-1969; 43522 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    Includes Park Slope Betterment Committee
  - Brownstone correspondence, 1969-1971; 43523 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Brownstone correspondence, 1971-1978; 43524 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    Includes Park Slope Betterment Committee, Brownstone Revival Committee, Back to the City, U.S. Congressman Fred Richmond, and U.S. Congresswoman Yvonne B. Burke
  - Brownstone correspondence, 1978-1985; 43525 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    Includes Brownstone Revival Committee, New York City Mayor Edward I. Koch, Brooklyn Borough President Howard Golden, and U.S. Congressman Leo C. Zeferetti
  - Brownstone correspondence and clippings, 2000-2005; 43608 (Box 16, Folder 2)
- Series 11: Brooklyn Union Gas Company - Cinderella projects, 1967-2008; 43620; 10 Linear Feet in nine folders, oversize folders, and five film canisters
  The series documents the Brooklyn Union Gas Company's Cinderella projects. Starting in the 1960s, the company purchased and refurbished abandoned brownstones in the Park Slope neighborhood of Brooklyn in order to attract new residents to the neighborhood. EGO designed and furnished the interiors of the first Cinderella home at 211 Berkeley Place in 1968, and EHO was vocal proponent of the program. In 1978 the Ortners recieved the company's Cinderella Award, and were featured in Brooklyn Union Gas Company advertisements.
  The series consists of publications, correspondence, films, histories on the program and the company, and ephemera, dating from 1968 to 2008. Of note are three 16mm films produced by the company to promote the program in the 1970s.
  - Brooklyn Union Gas Company annual report, 1967; 43621 (Box 24, Folder 9)
  - 211 Berkeley Place clippings and correspondence to EGO, 1968; 43622 (Box 24, Folder 10)
  - Brooklyn Union, Cinderella, and the Ortners, 1970s-1999; 43623 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Brooklyn Union Gas Company, 1970-1976; 43624 (Box 24, Folder 12)
  - Brooklyn Union Gas Company - Brownstones of Brooklyn films (3 copies), 1972; 49533 (Bin 2014.003.11.1-3, Reel -)
  - Brooklyn Union Gas Company - Cinderella of Berkeley Place (?) film, circa 1972; 49535 (Reel 2014.003.11.4, Reel -)
  - Brooklyn Union Gas Company - Cinderella of Prospect Place film, circa 1972; 49534 (Bin 2014.003.11.5, Reel -)
  - Brooklyn Union - Costumes, 1972-1973; 43626 (Box 24, Folder 13)
  - Brooklyn Union Gas - Cinderella contact sheet, 1976; 43625 (Box 24, Folder 14)
  - Brooklyn Union Gas Company - Cinderella project newspaper advertisements, 1976-1977; 49406 (Box 75, Folder -)
  - Brooklyn Union Gas Company - Ortners/Cinderella award winners posters, 1978; 49412 (Box 76, Folder -)
  - Brooklyn Union, 1997-1998; 43627 (Box 24, Folder 15)
  - Typescripts on Brooklyn Union Gas Company, Keyspan, and National Grid by EHO, 2006; 43628 (Box 24, Folder 16)
  - Brooklyn Union Gas Company's Cinderella Projects by Elizabeth Soloman, 2008; 43629 (Box 24, Folder 17)
    Includes edits by EHO
- Series 12: Historic District Designation Reports, 1969-1973, 2005; 43630; 0.3 Linear Feet in nine folders
  Arranged alphabetically.
  The series contains New York City Historic District Designation Reports (1969-1973) and one map of historic locations in the Greenpoint and Williamsburg neighborhoods of Brooklyn (2005). The Ortners were key proponents of the landmarking of the Park Slope neighborhood of Brooklyn, and their photographs of Park Slope buildings were used to support the establishment of the historic district. The series also includes negatives and contact sheets of 272-276 Berkeley Place.
  - Carroll Gardens Historic Designation Report, 1973; 43631 (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - Cobble Hill Historic Designation Report, 1969; 43632 (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - Greenpoint - Williamsburg Historic Resources Map, 2005; 43633 (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - Greenwich Village Historic Designation Report, 1969; 43634 (Box 24, Folder 21)
  - Park Slope Historic Designation Reports (3 folders), 1973; 43635 (Box 25, Folder 1-3)
    Includes negatives and contact sheets of 272-276 Berkeley Place
  - Stuyvesant Heights Historic Designation Report, 1971; 43636 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Upper West Side Historic Designation Reports, 1973; 43637 (Box 25, Folder 5)
- Series 13: Brooklyn and Manhattan postcards, 1873-2007; 44024; 0.7 Linear Feet in one small box (Box 52, Folder -)
  The series is divided into Brooklyn postcards, Manhattan postcards, and other postcards.
  The series contains Brooklyn and Manhattan postcards and a small amount of other postcards and tradecards (Rising Sun Stove Polish and Paine's Funiture Manufactory) collected by Everett Ortner, dating from 1873 to 2007.